I'm going to begin today with a story
سأبدأ اليوم بقصة
and end with a revolution.
وسأنتهي بثورة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Are you ready?
هل أنتم مستعدون؟
Audience: Yes!
الجمهور: نعم!
Naomi McDougall-Jones: Here's the story.
ناعومي مكدوغال جونز: إليكم القصة.
All my life I wanted to be an actress.
طوال حياتي أردت أن أكون ممثلة.
From the time I was very small, I could feel the magic of storytelling
منذ كنت صغيرة، كنت أشعر بسحر رواية القصص
and I wanted to be a part of it.
وأردت أن أصبح جزءًا منه
So, at the ripe age of 21,
عندما بلغت العمر المناسب 21 سنة،
I graduated from the American Academy of Dramatic Arts
تخرجت من الأكاديمية الأمريكية للفن الدرامي
in New York City,
في مدينة نيويورك،
bright-eyed and bushy-tailed, and ready to take my rightful place
منفتحة الأعين ومتحمسة، ومستعدة لأخذ مكاني المناسب
as the next Meryl Streep.
كـ ميريل ستريب التالية.
That's my grandmother, not Meryl Streep.
هذه جدتي، ليست ميريل ستريب.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Now, it's important for this story that you understand
من المهم للقصة أن تفهم
I mean, just to give you some idea:
أقصد، كي تأخذ فكرة عن الموضوع:
when I was five or six years old and obsessed with "The Sound of Music,"
عندما كنت بعمر الستة أو خمسة سنوات، ومهووسة بـ"صوت الموسيقى"
and running around, singing, "I am 16 going on 17,"
كنت أجري وأغني "أنا 16 وسأصبح 17"
all day every day,
طوال اليوم في كل يوم
my mother sat me down for a very serious conversation
أجلستني والدتي من أجل محادثة جدية جدًا
and she said, "OK, look.
وقالت لي: حسنًا، انظري.
I'm not going to say that you can't sing that song,
لن أخبرك أنك لا تستطيعين أن تغني تلك الأغنية،
but if you are going to sing that song, I do need you to understand
لكن إن كنت ستغنينها، أريدك أن تفهمي
the extremely problematic gender construct that it reinforces."
المعتقد الجنسي الخاطئ بشدة الذي تعززه هذه الأغنية
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So that's where I come from.
إذًا من هنا أتيت.
So it just honestly never even occurred to me
في الحقيقة لم يحدث ذلك لي أبدًا
that I would be prevented from doing anything in my life
أن أُمنع من فعل أي شيء في حياتي
OK. So I graduate.
حسناً، لقد تخرجت.
And I start auditioning and I get work, slowly.
وبدأت أذهب إلى تجارب الأداء وأحصل على عمل تدريجيًا.
But I just start noticing that the parts available for women
لكن لاحظت أن الأدوار المتاحة للنساء
are terrible.
بالغة بالسوء.
But, remember -- I came here
أتذكر، أتيت إلى هنا
to play smart, willful, complicated, interesting
كي أمثل شخصيات نسائية ذكية ومعقدة ومثيرة
complex, confident female characters, right?
وصعبة وواثقة، صحيح؟
Like Meryl.
مثل ميرل.
And all of the sudden,
ولكن فجأة،
I am wrestling with 300 other gorgeous, talented women
كنت أتصارع مع 300 امرأة فاتنة وموهوبة
to play ...
كي أمثل ...
"[Female] No dialogue.
"[إمرأة] لا حوار.
The character only needs to stand on a balcony,
الشخصية يتوجب عليها فقط أن تقف على شرفة،
look forlorn, and walk back inside the house.
أن تبدو حزينة، وتعود لداخل المنزل.
Only partial nudity."
تعري جزئي فقط".
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
"[Sarah] Brian's love interest.
[سارة] حبيبة بريان المثيرة للاهتمام
Attractive, cute, and flirty, she is the ideal girl and Brian's prize
جذابة وظريفة ومثيرة إنها الفتاة المثالية وجائزة بريان
throughout the entire film."
خلال كامل الفلم."
"[Mom] A proper Southern belle who is making peace with the fact
"[الأم] امرأة مناسبة وجميلة من الجنوب متعايشة مع واقع
that her only purpose in life is to tend to her husband."
أن الغرض الوحيد لها في الحياة هي أن تعتني بزوجها
"[Abby] Must be OK with a tastefully shot gang rape,
[آبي] يجب أن تقبل الظهور بمشهد اغتصاب جماعي
along with performing 19th-century dance."
مع أداء رقصة من القرن 19
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Those are actual casting notices.
هذه ملاحظات حقيقة لاختيار الممثلين
And so I just mentioned this to my agent one day,
وقد ذكرت ذلك مرة لأحد الموظِفين،
I say, "I feel like I'm not really going in for parts
قلت له: "لا أظن أنني أمثل الأدوار
that I'm actually excited about playing.
التي أنا متحمسة تجاهها بالفعل."
And he said, "Yeah. I don't really know what to do with you.
وقال: "أجل، لا أدري ماذا أفعل معك.
You're too smart for the parts
أنتِ ذكية جدًا لتلك الأدوار
that are being written for women in their 20s,
التي كتبت للنساء في العشرينات من عمرهن،
so I think you'll work when you're 35."
لذلك أعتقد أنك ستبدأين بالعمل بعمر 35 سنة"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And I said, "Oh. That's funny.
وقلت:اووه، هذا مضحك.
I always thought that when you were 35, you were kind of, like,
لطالما اعتقدت أنكِ عندما تصبحين بعمر ال35، تصبحين
that you were relegated to playing 20-year-olds' mothers."
لذلك ستتنازلين كي تؤدي أدوار أمهات بعمر العشرين
And he said, "Yeah --
وقال: "صحيح...
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
It's just the way it is."
هكذا تجري الأمور."
So, maybe a year or so after this,
ربما بعد سنة أو أكثر،
I'm having lunch with an actress friend of mine,
كنت أتناول الغداء مع ممثلة والتي كانت صديقة لي
and we're talking about how insane this is.
وكنا نتكلم كم أن هذا غير معقول.
And we decide, you know what? No problem.
وقررنا، أتدري ماذا؟ لا مشكلة.
We'll just make our own movie.
سنقوم بتصوير فيلم خاص بنا.
And I'll write and then I'll write it about two complex female characters.
وسأكتب النص بنفسي عن شخصيتين نسائيتين معقدتين
So we do.
وهكذا فعلنا.
We set out to make this movie,
وجهزنا أنفسنا لصنع هذا الفيلم،
and sort of accidentally, we end up hiring an all-female production team:
وبطريقة ما، انتهى بنا الأمر بتوظيف فريق كامل من النساء
the writer, directors, producers,
الكتاب والمخرجون والمنتجون،
and it's a film about two women.
وهو فلم عن امرأتين.
And so pretty soon, we're sitting in the office
وبعد ذلك بفترة، كنا جالسون بمكتب
of a successful male producer,
رجل إنتاج ناجح،
and he goes, "OK, girls.
وقال: "حسنًا يا فتيات.
So, you do understand that at some point you are going to have to hire
أنتم تعلمون أنه في نقطة ما سيتوجب عليكم تعيين
a male producer onboard, right?
منتج ذكر، صحيح؟
Just so that people will trust you with their money."
فقط كي يثق الناس بكم ويستثمرون أموالهم فيكم."
Over and over again, people tell us,
مجددًا ومجددًا، يخبرنا الناس
"Yeah, but people don't really want to see films about women,
"صحيح، لكن الناس لا تريد حقًا مشاهدة أفلام عن النساء،
so maybe you should think about making something else.
ربما يجب أن تفكروا بشيء آخر.
It's just the way it is."
هكذا تسير الأمور."
So we make the movie, anyway.
لكننا صنعنا الفيلم على كل حال.
We scrape together 80,000 dollars,
جمعنا 80,000 دولار،
and we make it, and it does so well.
وفعلناها، ونجح الفيلم
It gets into tons of festivals and we win a lot of awards
دخل الفيلم العديد من المسابقات وربحنا العديد من الجوائز
and it's big and exciting.
كان كبيرًا وحماسيًا.
But these experiences I've had just keep rubbing at me.
لكن هذه الخبرات التي حصلت عليها بقيت تجول بخاطري
And so, I just start talking about them,
لذلك بدأت أتحدث عنهم،
first, at Q and A's after screenings of the film,
بدأت بـسؤال وجواب بعد عرض الفلم،
and then I get invited to be on panels and talk at conferences.
وبعدها دعيت إلى بعض اللقاءات وإلى التحدث بالمؤتمرات
And the really amazing thing is that, to begin with,
والشيء المذهل كي أبدأ به هو أنه
when I'm just talking to audiences
عندما أتكلم مع الجماهير
and other people, you know, coming up in the film industry,
والناس الآخرون في مجال صناعة الأفلام،
the universal reaction is,
دائمًا ما تكون ردة الفعل،
"Oh my god! This is terrible. What do we do about this?"
"يا إلهي هذا فظيع ماذا سنفعل حيال هذا؟."
But the bigger panels I get on,
لكن في اللقاءات الأكبر التي ذهبت إليها،
suddenly an Oscar nominee tells me,
فجأة قال لي مرشح لجائزة أوسكار
"Look, I totally agree with everything you're saying.
"أنظري، أنا أتفق مع كلامك تمامًا.
You just need to be really careful about where you say it."
لكن يجب عليك أن تحذري حول المكان الذي تقولينه فيه."
An Oscar-winning producer tells me
أخبرتني منتجة رابحة لجائزة الأوسكار
that she doesn't think it's a good idea to play the woman card.
أنها لا تظن أنها فكرة جيدة أن تستغلي كونك امرأة
It's just the way it is.
هكذا تسير الأمور
And I think this is how sexism continues on in 2016, right?
هكذا يستمر التمييز الجنسي حتى 2016 صحيح؟
For the most part, it happens casually --
أغلب الأحيان، يحدث عرضًا
unconsciously, even.
بشكل غير واعي حتى.
It happens because people are just trying to get along
يحدث لأن الناس تحاول أن تتماشى
within an existing system.
مع نظام مسبق.
It happens, maybe, out of a genuine desire
يحدث أحيانًا انطلاقاً من رغبة صادقة
to teach a young woman the way that the world "just is."
أن تقوم بتعليم امرأة شابة كيف يكون العالم كما هو.
The problem is that unless we do something about it,
المشكلة أنه إذا لم نقم بشيء حيال هذا،
that is the way the world will always be.
سيبقى العالم هكذا للأبد.
So why should you care about this?
لكن لم يجب أن تهتم بهذا ؟
Right?
صحيح؟
I mean, we're facing some rather significant problems in the world
أقصد، نواجه مشاكل أكثر أهمية في العالم
just at present,
ما الفرق إذا لم أحصل أنا على عمل،
Well, let me put it to you this way:
حسنًا، دعني أصيغها بهذا الشكل:
the year "Jaws" came out,
حين صدر فيلم الفكين،
Americans suddenly started listing "sharks" among their top 10 major fears.
بدأ الأمريكيون بتدوين القروش ضمن لائحتهم لأكثر 10 أشياء رعبًا
In 1995, BMW paid the James Bond franchise three million dollars
في 1995، BMW دُفعت لجيمس بوند ثلاثة ملايين دولار
to have James Bond switch from driving an Aston Martin
لكي يقود بدلأ من سيارة إستون مارتن
to a BMW Z3.
سيارة BMW Z3
That one move caused so many people to go out and buy that car,
هذه الحركة البسيطة جعلت الكثير من الناس يشترون تلك السيارة،
that BMW made 240 million dollars in pre-sales alone.
هذه الـ BMW حققت 240 مليون دولار حتى قبل أن تطرح في السوق.
The year that "Brave" and "Hunger Games" came out,
السنة التي صدر بها فلمي "بريف" و"هنغر غيمز"،
female participation in archery went up 105 percent.
ارتفعت نسبة النساء المشاركات في الرماية بنسبة 105%
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
In fact, studies show
في الحقيقة، تظهر الدراسات
that the movies you watch don't just affect your hobbies,
أن الأفلام التي تشاهدها لا تؤثر على عاداتك فحسب،
they affect your career choices, your emotions, your sense of identity,
تأثر أيضًا على اختيارك لمهنتك وعلى عواطفك وهَويتك.
your relationships, your mental health -- even your marital status.
علاقاتك وصحتك العقلية حتى علاقتك الزوجبة.
So now, consider this:
لذلك، خذ هذا بالاعتبار:
if you have watched mostly American movies in your lifetime,
إذا كان معظم الأفلام التي شاهدتها في حياتك أمريكية
95 percent of all the films you have ever seen
95% من كل الأفلام التي شاهدتها
were directed by men.
أخرجها رجال.
Somewhere between 80 and 90 percent of all of the leading characters
في بعض الأماكن بين 80 و 90 بالمئة من كل الشخصيات الرئيسية
that you have ever seen
التي شاهدتها في حياتك
were men.
كانوا رجالًا.
And even if we just talk about the last five years,
حتى إذا تحدثنا عن خمس سنين مضت.
55 percent of the time that you have seen a woman in a movie,
55 بالمئة من الوقت الذي شاهدت فيه امرأة بفيلم،
she was naked or scantily clad.
كانت عارية أو شبه عارية.
That affects you.
هذا يؤثر فيك.
That affects all of us.
يؤثر علينا جميعًا.
We actually can't even imagine how much it affects us,
لا نستطيع أن نتخيل كم أن هذا يؤثر فينا.
because this is all we've ever had.
لأن هذا هو كل ما حصلنا عليه.
Stories -- and movies are just modern stories --
القصص والأفلام التي هي مجرد قصص حديثة
are not frivolous.
ليست بالأمر التافه
They're actually the mechanism through which we process
هم في الواقع الآلية التي من خلالها نكتسب
our experience of being alive.
خبرتنا في البقاء أحياء
They're the way that we understand the world
هم الطريقة التي نفهم بها العالم
and our place in it.
ومكاننا فيه.
They're the way we develop empathy
هم الطريقة التي نطور بها التعاطف
for people who have experiences different than our own.
تجاه الأشخاص الذين لديهم تجارب مختلفة عنا.
And right now, all of that is being funneled at us
وفي الوقت الحالي، كل شيء يصل إلينا
through the prism of this one perspective.
من وجهة نظر واحدة،
It's not that it's a bad perspective,
لا يعني هذا أنها وجهة نظر سيئة،
but don't we deserve to hear them all?
لكن ألا نستحق أن نسمع جميع وجهات النظر؟
How would the world be different if all of the stories were told?
كم سيصبح العالم مختلفًأ لو أن جميع القصص رُويت؟
So what do we do about this?
إذا ماذا نفعل حيال هذا؟
This may be the first time a lot of you are hearing about this,
قد تكون هذه المرة الأولى التي تسمعون بها هذا
but a lot of us within the film industry have spent years --
لكن الكثير منّا قضى أعوامًا في مجال صناعة الأفلام
a lot of people, a lot longer than I have --
الكثير من الناس قضوا أكثر بكثير مني
giving speeches and doing panels and writing articles
وهم يلقون الخطابات ويحضرون اللقاءات ويكتبون المقالات
and doing studies,
ويقومون بالدراسات،
and really just yelling at Hollywood to do a better job about this.
ويصرخون على هوليوود كي يحسنوا من هذا الوضع
I mean, we have really yelled at them.
أقصد، نحن صرخنا عليهم بالفعل.
And yet, Paramount and Fox recently released their slates,
ومع ذلك، قام بارامونت وفوكس بنشر لائحات لأفلامهم في المستقبل
and of the 47 films that they will release between now and 2018,
ومن أصل 47 فلم سينشرون من الآن وحتى 2017
not a single one will be directed by a woman.
ولا واحد منهم ستخرجه امرأة.
So it is beginning to occur to me
وبدأت أرى
that waiting for Hollywood to grow a conscience
أن الانتظار كي يصحو ضمير هوليوود
may not actually be a winning strategy.
قد لا يكون استراتيجية رابحة.
In fact, it seems to me
في الحقيقة يبدو لي
that whenever there is a small, ruling class of people
أنه عندما يكون هناك طبقة مسيطرة من الناس
who have all of the money and power and resources,
الذين لديهم الأموال والقوة والموارد،
they're not actually that excited about giving it up.
لا يكونون مستعدين للتخلي عنها.
And so you don't get change by asking them
ولذلك لن تحصل على التغيير عن طريق السؤال
or even yelling at them.
أو حتى الصراخ عليهم
You have to make that change happen
عليك أن تحقق ذلك التغيير
through a revolution.
عن طريق ثورة
Now, please don't worry -- I promise you, here, now, today,
رجاء لا تقلقوا، أعدكم، هنا والآن واليوم
our body count will be very low.
عدد القتلى بيننا سيكون قليل.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So, now before I get to my four-point plan for the revolution --
وقبل أن أصل إلى خطتي رباعية النقاط للثورة
yes, I have a four-point plan --
أجل لدي خطة ذات أربعة نقاط
I have two pieces of very good and important news for you.
لدي أخبار جيدة ومهمة لكم
Good news number one:
الخبر الجيد الأول:
there are female filmmakers.
هناك صانعي أفلام نساء.
(Cheers and applause)
(هتاف وتصفيق)
Yes! I know!
أجل! أعلم!
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
We exist!
نحن موجودون!
We actually graduate from film schools
تخرجنا في الحقيقة من مدارس السينما
at the same rate that men do -- 50 percent.
بنسبة مساوية لعدد الرجال المتخرجين 50 بالمئة.
So here we have our 50 women.
لدينا هنا 50 امرأة.
The problem is that as soon as you get to the micro-budget film,
المشكلة هو أنه عندما تصل للأفلام منخفضة الميزانية،
so even the very smallest films,
حتى أصغر الأفلام.
we're already only directing 18 percent.
لا نخرج منها إلا 18 بالمئة.
Then you get to slightly bigger films,
وبعدها نصل للأفلام الأكبر بقليل.
indies in the $1-5 million budget range,
بميزانية تتراوح بين 1-5 مليون دولار
and we go down to 12 percent.
فننخفض إلى 12 بالمئة.
So by the time you get to the studio system,
وعندما نصل إلى نظام الاستديو،
we're only directing five percent of movies.
يصبح إخراجنا للأفلام خمسة بالمئة فقط.
Now, I know some of you out there will look at this
أعرف أن بعض منكم سينظر لهذا
and secretly think to yourselves,
ويفكر بينه وبين نفسه،
"Well, maybe women just aren't as good at directing movies."
"ربما النساء ليسوا جيدين بإخراج الأفلام."
And that's not a totally insane question.
وهذا ليس سؤالًا غبيًا تمامًا.
I mean, we like to believe the film industry is a meritocracy, right?
نحن نريد أن نصدق أن صناعة الأفلام تعمل على مبدأ الجدارة، صحيح؟
(Laughs)
(تضحك)
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But look at this trajectory.
لكن انظروا إلى هذا المسار.
Either you have to accept
إما أن تصدق أن
that women are actually five percent as talented as men,
النساء في الحقيقة موهوبات بقدر 5 بالمئة من موهبة الرجال،
which I don't,
وأنا لا أصدق هذا،
or you have to accept that there are serious systemic issues
أو أن تصدق أن هناك مشاكل خطيرة في النظام
preventing us from getting from here to there.
تمنعنا من الوصول من هنا إلى هناك.
But the good news is, we exist,
لكن الأخبار الجيدة هي، نحن موجودون،
and there is a vast amount of untapped potential over here.
وهناك قدر ضخم من القدرات غير المستثمرة هنا
Good news number two, and this is really good news:
الخبر الجيد رقم اثنان، وهذا خبر جيد بالفعل:
films by and about women make more money.
أفلام النساء تحقق أرباحًا أكثر.
Yes! Yes! It's true!
أجل! أجل! هذا صحيح!
(Cheers and applause)
(هتاف وتصفيق)
It's true.
هذا صحيح
The Washington Post recently released a study
نشرت صحيفة واشنطن دراسة مؤخرًا
showing that films that feature women make 23 cents more on every dollar
تظهر أن الأفلام التي تتضمن النساء تحقق ربح 23 سنت فوق كل دولار
than films that don't.
من الأفلام التي لا تفعل.
Furthermore, my colleagues and I commissioned a study
أكثر من ذلك، أنا وزملائي قمنا بعمل دراسة
comparing 1,700 films made over the last five years
بمقارنة 1700 فيلم من الخمس سنين الماضية
and, looking at the average returns on investment --
والنظر إلى معدل العائدات من الاستثمار
so, how much money does that movie make --
كم يحقق الفيلم
director, producer, screenwriter and lead actor.
مخرج، منتج، وممثل رئيسي،
And in every single category,
وفي كل فئة،
the return on investment is higher if it's a woman.
عائدات الأرباح أعلى إذا كان ذلك الشخص امرأة.
Fact: women buy 51 percent of all movie tickets.
حقيقة: النساء تشتري 51 بالمئة من كل تذاكر الأفلام.
Films by and about women make more money.
أفلام النساء تحقق أرباحًا أكثر.
And of course, at least some portion of the male population
وبالطبع، على الأقل نسبةٌ ما من الرجال
does also like women --
تحقق ما تحقق النساء
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
so "women films" are not just for women.
إذَا "أفلام النساء" ليست فقط للنساء.
And yet, Hollywood only targets 18 percent of all of their films
ومع ذلك، هوليوود تنتج 18 بالمئة فقط من جميع أفلامها
as "women films."
كـ "أفلام نساء"
So what you're left with is a giant underserved audience
وهذا يتركك مع جمهور ضخم محروم
and untapped profit potential.
وقدرات مربحة غير مستثمرة.
So we exist, and we have stories to tell.
إذًا نحن موجودون، ولدينا قصص لنرويها.
We have so many stories to tell.
لدينا الكثير من القصص لنرويها.
And despite everything we've heard: you want to see them.
وبغض النظر عن كل شيء سمعناه، أنت تريد أن تراهم.
The problem is, we've got this thing -- let's call it "Hollywood" --
لكن المشكلة، لدينا هذا الشيء المسمى "هوليوود"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
no, no, I'm just kidding;
لا لا أنا أمزح
I've met some very nice people in Hollywood --
قابلت بعض الأشخاص الرائعين في هوليوود
Hollywood, preventing us from getting to you.
هوليوود، تمنعنا من الوصول إليكم.
So here is my four-point plan for the revolution,
ها هي خطتي الرباعية للثورة،
and everybody -- man or woman, in this room or anywhere in the world --
والجميع -رجلًا أو امرأةً، في هذه الغرفة أو في أي مكان بالعالم-
is going to get to help.
سيحصل على المساعدة.
And this revolution is not just for women.
وهذه الثورة ليست فقط للنساء.
Anyone who has been disenfranchised,
بل لأي شخص محروم من حقوقه،
anyone whose story has not been told,
أي شخص قصته لم تُروى،
the same principles apply,
نفس المبادئ تطبق،
and I really hope we can do the revolution together.
وأنا آمل أن نثور معًا.
My four-point plan.
خطتي ذات الأربعة نقاط.
Number one: watch movies.
رقم واحد: شاهد الأفلام.
Isn't this a good revolution?
أليست هذه بثورة جيدة؟
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
OK, first I want to talk to anyone who watches movies.
حسنٌ، بالبداية أريد أن أتحدث إلى أي شخص يشاهد الأفلام
Who watches movies in here?
من يشاهد الأفلام هنا؟
Great!
رائع!
Will you pledge to watch one film by a female filmmaker per month?
هل تقطع عهدًأ أن تشاهد فلم واحد مصنوع من قبل امرأة في الشهر؟
That's it, just start there. Great!
هذه هي، فقط ابدأ هنا. رائع!
If you need help finding them,
إذا أردت مساعدة بإيجادهم،
you can go to the website, moviesbyher.com
يمكنك زيارة موقع moviesbyher.com
It's an easily searchable database of films by women.
إنه قاعدة بيانات سهلة تدعم البحث للأفلام المصنوعة من قبل النساء.
And as you start watching all movies,
وبينما تشاهد أي فيلم،
I just want you to pay attention to the female characters.
أريدك أن تنتبه إلى الشخصيات النسائية.
How many of them are there?
كم يوجد منهم؟
What are they wearing?
ماذا يرتدون؟
Or not?
أم أنهم لا يرتدون؟
Do they get to do cool things,
هل يقومون بفعل أشياء جيدة،
or are they just there to emotionally support the men?
أم أنهم هناك لدعم الرجال عاطفيًا؟
I'm telling you, once you see this, you're not going to be able to unsee it.
أنا أخبركم، حالما تشاهد هذا، لن تستطيع تجاهل الأمر.
And as you start noticing this, it's going to shift your viewing habits.
وبينما تبدأ بملاحظة هذا، ستبدأ عادات المشاهدة لديك بالتغير.
And this already sizable market is going to continue to grow.
وسيستمر المستهلكون لهذه الأفلام بالتزايد.
Step two: make movies.
الخطوة الثانية: اصنع الأفلام.
So now I'm talking to all the female filmmakers out there:
أنا أتحدث إلى كل صانعي الأفلام النساء هناك
we need you to be very brave.
نريدك أن تكوني شجاعة جدًا.
It will be harder for you to make movies.
سيكون أصعب عليكِ أن تصنعي الأفلام.
In fact, there will be an entire industry constantly telling you
في الحقيقة، سيكون هناك صناعة كاملة تخبرك باستمرار
that your stories don't matter.
أن قصصكِ لا تهم.
And we need you to make them, anyway.
لكننا نريدكِ أن تصنعيهم في كل الأحوال.
That 18 percent in the micro-budget range -- that is on us to fix.
تلك الـ 18 بالمئة في نطاق معدل الميزانية المنخفصة، نحن من يجب أن يجد حلًا لها
Don't wait for permission.
لا تنتظري للإذن
Don't wait for somebody to pick you,
لا تنتظري أحدًا كي يساعدك،
Crowd fund.
احصلي على التمويل،
Write letters to eccentric relatives.
اكتبي رسائل لأقربائك الغريبين
I know how hard it is,
أعرف كم أن هذا صعب،
but you have to make your movies -- now, today, features, not shorts.
لكن يجب عليكي أن تصنعي أفلامك الآن واليوم، طويلة لا قصيرة.
There is an audience for them, and they want and need to see them.
هناك جمهور لهم، يريدون ويتوجب عليهم أن يشاهدوهم.
Three: invest in each other.
ثالثًأ: استثمروا بين بعضكم.
Fellow female filmmakers, I feel like we need to stop wasting so much energy
اتبعي صانعات الأفلام، أظن أنه يجب أن نتوقف عن إضاعة الكثير من الطاقة
on a system that does not want us.
على نظام لا يريدنا.
We need to find our audience and invest in cultivating them.
يجب علينا أن نجد جمهورنا وأن نعمل على تكبيره.
If we can figure out how to make our movies
إذا استطعنا أن نصنع أفلامنا
and deliver them to the audiences that want them,
وأن نوصلهم إلى الجماهير التي تريدهم
that's it.
فهذه هي.
That's the whole game.
هذه هي كل اللعبة.
And whatever they're doing in the middle
وأيًا يكن الذي يفعلونه في الوسط
is going to cease to be quite so important.
لن يكون مؤثرًا بعد ذلك.
Audiences, invest in us.
يا جماهير، استثمروا فينا
Help us make the movies that you want to see.
ساعدونا بأن نصنع الأفلام التي تريدون رؤيتها.
If you can give a female filmmaker 25 dollars in a crowdfunding campaign,
إذا استطعت أن تعطي لصانعة أفلام 25 دولار في عملية جمع التمويل
great, do that.
فذلك سيكون رائعًا، افعلها.
If you can invest more seriously
إذا استطعت أن تستثمر بشكل أفضل
and help us over that critical million-dollar hurdle,
وأن تساعدنا في أن نتغلب على عائق المليون دولار،
do that.
افعلها.
But invest in seeing the other half of the story.
لكن استثمر كي ترى النصف الثاني من القصة.
Four: disrupt through business.
رابعًا: قاطع عن طريق الأعمال التجارية
So now I'm talking to all of the businesspeople
الآن أنا أتحدث مع كل رجال ونساء الأعمال
and entrepreneurs.
ورواد الأعمال.
This does not happen very often in the world,
هذا لا يحدث كثيرًا في العالم،
but right here we have a golden situation
لكن هنا لدينا حالة ذهبية
in which you can enact significant social change
والتي يمكنك أن تحقق بها تغييرًا اجتماعيًا مهمًا
while also making money.
بينما تجني الأموال.
Hollywood is a system ripe for disruption.
نظام هوليوود قابل للمقاطعة.
The old models of financing and distribution are crumbling --
الطرق القديمة للتمويل والتوزيع هشة
please come in and disrupt it.
رجاءً تعالوا وقاطعوها.
I'll give you an example.
سأعطيكم مثالًَا.
Right now, with some incredible women,
في الوقت الحالي، مع بعض النساء الرائعات
I am launching the "The 51 Fund."
أشغل مشروع "The 51 fund"
It's a venture capital fund
إنه صندوق رأس مال استثماري
that will finance films written, directed and produced by women
سيموّل الأفلام المكتوبة والمخرجة والمنتجة من قبل النساء
in that critical $1-5 million range.
في مجال 1-5 مليون دولار.
We will give a significant number of female filmmakers
سنعطي الكثير من صانعات الأفلام
the chance to make their movies
الفرصة كي يصنعوا أفلامهم
and we will deliver them to the audiences who want them.
وسنوصلهم إلى الجماهير التي تريدهم.
Good for equality, good for business.
أمرٌ جيد للمساواة وجيد للأعمال.
But that's only one example, we need more.
ولكن هذا مثال واحد، ونحن نحتاج المزيد.
There is room for so many more.
هناك مساحة لأكثر من ذلك بكثير.
So I say to you:
أقول لكم،
Hollywood is leaving money on the table.
هوليوود تترك أموالًا على الطاولة.
Come pick it up.
تعالوا وخذوها.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Now, all of this may seem like a lot, but it is actually so doable.
الآن كل هذا قد يبدو الكثير، لكنه قابل للتنفيذ.
Entrenched systems don't change because you ask the people in charge,
الأنظمة المتينة لا تتغيرعن طريق طلب ذلك من المسؤولين عنها،
they change because all of the people who don't have what they want
تتغير بسبب جميع الناس الذين ليس لديهم ما يريدون
rise up and make that change happen.
ينهضون ويحققون ذلك التغيير.
And don't you want to?
ألا تريد ذلك؟
I want to see what the other 51 percent of the population has to say.
أريد أن أسمع ماذا لدى الـ51 بالمئة الأخرى من الناس ليقولونه
I want to watch movies that teach me about people
أريد أن أشاهد الأفلام التي تعلمني عن الناس
who are different than I am.
المختلفين عني.
I want to see women's bodies on film that aren't perfect.
أريد أن أرى أجساد النساء غير المثالية في الأفلام.
I want to give our little boys the chance
أريد أن أمنح الفرصة لأولادنا الصغار
to empathize with female characters
كي يتعاطفوا مع الشخصيات النسائية
so that they can become more whole men.
فيصبحون رجالًا كاملين
And I definitely want to give a little girl
وحتمًا أريد أن أمنح طفلةً صغيرة
who may not have a real-life role model
والتي ربما لا تملك قدوة حقيقية
the chance to watch movies
الفرصة كي تشاهد الأفلام
and see women doing everything she dreams of achieving.
وترى النساء ينجزن كل شيء حلمت بإنجازه.
This is not about making one industry better.
الأمر ليس عن تحسين صناعة واحدة.
This is about making a better world.
بل عن تحسين العالم.
Will you help?
هل ستساعد؟
The time for waiting is over.
وقت الانتظار انتهى.
The time for the revolution is now.
وقت الثورة حان.
(Cheers and applause)
(هتاف وتصفيق)